James Simmons papers, 1945-1996
Emory University
- Printed material, Series 6; Boxes 71-77, OP 11-20
  - Writings by Simmons, Subseries 6.1; Box 71
    - "An Unpolitical Ulsterman," in Phase 1, 4 December 1968 [See also Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1] (Box 71, Folder 74)
    - "The Use of History" (Box 71, Folder 75)
    - "Virtue is Not Dull," [review of Henry James's What Maisie Knew] (Box 71, Folder 76)
  - Writings about Simmons, Subseries 6.2; Box 72-74; OP 11-15
    - Reviews
    - "Anatomizing Very Human Pain," by Richard Hayes in the Irish Literary Supplement, Spring 1996 [review of Elegies] (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - "Breath of Fresh Dare," by Damian Gorman, in Irish News [review of From the Irish] (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - "Cassettes of Atrocity," by Peter Porter in the Observer, 31 August 1985 [review of From the Irish] (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - "Chancy," by Bernard O'Donoghue in Poetry Review, June 1987 [review of Poems 1956-1986] (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - "Collected Poems," by Timothy Brownlow in Hibernia [review of Late but in Earnest] [See Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - "A Dazzle of Poets," in the Irish Press, 21 September 1974 [review of Ten Irish Poets] (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - "Death & Other Weaknesses," in Irish Press, 4 September 1980 [review of Constantly Singing] (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - "Direct Routes," by John S. Kelly, in the Irish Press, 2 April 1969 [review of In the Wilderness] [See Subseries, 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - "400 Saucy Verses," by H.L. Williams, in Western Mail, 1 March 1969 [review of In the Wilderness] [See Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - "From the Irish," by Terry Eagleton in Poetry Review, Summer 1985 [review of From the Irish] (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - "Gruesomely Gooey," by John Lucas in the New Statesman, 20 September 1985 [review of From the Irish] (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - "The Hard Edge of Culture," by Gordon Wardman [review of Poems 1956-1986] (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - "The Honest Ulsterman," in Community Mirror, June 1978 [review of The Selected James Simmons] (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - "The Importance of Being Sean," by Michael O hAodha in Irish Times, 24 March 1984 [review of Sean O'Casey] (Box 72, Folder 11)
    - "An Irishman Well-Versed in Spleen," by Lachlan Mackinnon in The Independent, 19 March 1987 [review of Poems 1956-1986] (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - "James Simmons...a Master of Allusion," by Frank Ormsby in Belfast Telegraph, 15 April 1985 [review of From the Irish] (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - "James Simmons and the Rhythm of Life," by Jennifer FitzGerald [review of The Selected James Simmons] (Box 72, Folder 14)
    - "Like a Skein of Geese," by Adam Thorpe in The Observer, 30 July 1995 [review of Mainstream] (Box 72, Folder 15)
    - "The Magazine Scene," in the Irish Press, 12 April 1969 [See Subseries, 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - "A Man Living Dangerously," by Malachi O'Doherty, in The Irish News, 2 January 1987 [review of Poems 1956-1986] (Box 72, Folder 16)
    - "Moral Profanity, Poetic Evangelism," by Thomas McCarthy in Fortnight, May 1987 [review of Poems 1956-1986] (Box 72, Folder 17)
    - "Music of the Jungle," by Fred Johnston [review of Mainstream] (Box 72, Folder 18)
    - "My Own Voice Bores Me...But Not That of 'Ulster's Minstrel Boy,'" by John Midgley in News Letter, 29 May 1971 [review of Energy to Burn] (Box 72, Folder 19)
    - "News-sheet Competition," in Staff, August 1978 [review of The Selected James Simmons] (Box 72, Folder 20)
    - "The Hot World," by Anthony Glavin [review of No Flies] [see Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - "More of a Performance Than a Poem," by Martin Seymour-Smith [review of Late but in Earnest] [See Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - "Not at Home," by Martin Dodsworth, in The Guardian, 31 January 1980 [review of The Selected James Simmons] (Box 72, Folder 21)
    - "One Cad, Two Fools-By-Choice," by P.J. Kavanagh, in The Guardian, 27 February 1969 [review of In the Wilderness] [See Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 4, Folder 1]
    - "One Night Stanzas," by Patrick Ramsey in Fortnight, January 1994 [review of Sex. Rectitude, and Loneliness] (Box 72, Folder 22)
    - "Only Our Misery is Genuine," by Alain Sinner [review of Poems 1956-1986] (Box 72, Folder 23)
    - "Physical Responses," by John Horder in Spectator, 27 October 1967 [review of Late but in Earnest] [See Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - "Poetic Voices From the North," by Bridget O'Toole, 24 July 1978 [review of The Selected James Simmons] (Box 72, Folder 24)
    - "Poetry in the Clouds," by Patrick Crotty in the Irish Times, 11 April 1992 [review of The Cattle Rustling] (Box 72, Folder 25)
    - "A Provocative Poet," by Anthony Bradley, in the Irish Literary Supplement, Fall 1987 [review of Poems 1956-1986] (Box 72, Folder 26)
    - "Rational Faith in the Republic of the Ordinary," by Robert Welch in The Honest Ulsterman, Spring 1986 [review of From the Irish] (Box 72, Folder 27)
    - "Recent Poetry," by Dennis O'Driscoll, in Hibernia, 31 August 1978 [review of The Selected James Simmons] (Box 72, Folder 28)
    - "Recent Poetry," by Douglas Sealy [review of Poems 1956-1986] (Box 72, Folder 29)
    - Review of Constantly Singing, by Brian Sexton in The Irish Weekly, 25 October 1980 (Box 72, Folder 30)
    - Review of Elegies, in Books Ireland, February 1996 (Box 72, Folder 31)
    - Review of From the Irish by Fleur Adcock (Box 72, Folder 32)
    - Review of From the Irish by Michael O'Higgins in Iron Magazine, October 1985-January 1986 (Box 72, Folder 33)
    - Review of From the Irish by Kevin Smyth in Gown Literary Supplement (Box 72, Folder 34)
    - Review of The Honest Ulsterman, by Jeanne Flood, Autumn 1969 [See Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - Review of Judy Garland and the Cold War, by Gerald Dawe in Fortnight, 4 February 1977 (Box 72, Folder 35)
    - Review of No Land is Waste, Dr. Eliot, by Michael Foley (Box 72, Folder 36)
    - Review of Poems 1956-1986, in the New Statesman, 17 April 1987 (Box 72, Folder 37)
    - Review of The Rostrevor Sessions by Angela Topping (Box 72, Folder 38)
    - Review of Sean O'Casey by Nicholas Grene (Box 72, Folder 39)
    - Review of Sean O'Casey, by Jeremy Rowe in Speech & Drama, Spring 1984 (Box 72, Folder 40)
    - Review of The Selected James Simmons, by Andrew Clark (Box 72, Folder 41)
    - Review of The Selected James Simmons, by Terry Eagleton in Stand (Box 72, Folder 42)
    - Review of The Selected James Simmons, by Robert Greacen in Irish Press, 8 June 1978 (Box 72, Folder 43)
    - Review of The Selected James Simmons, by D.H. Millar in Ulster Tatler, June 1978 (Box 72, Folder 44)
    - Review of The Selected James Simmons, by Hayden Murphy in Aquarius, 1979 (Box 72, Folder 45)
    - Review of The Selected James Simmons, in Andersonstown News, 3 June 1978 (Box 72, Folder 46)
    - "Sex, Death and the Elemental," by Raymond J. Ross, in Cencrastus, Autumn 1987 [review of Poems 1956-1986] (Box 72, Folder 47)
    - "Sheer Simmons," by Jim McDowell in News Letter, 10 May 1978 [review of The Selected James Simmons] (Box 72, Folder 48)
    - "Singing and Roaring," by Gavin Ewart in The Times Literary Supplement, 28 July 1978 [review of The Selected James Simmons] (Box 72, Folder 49)
    - "Smooth Songs and Irish Echoes," in The Times Literary Supplement, 24 April 1969 [review of In the Wilderness] [See Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - "Some New Strain," by Andrew Motion in the New Statesman, 26 September 1980 [review of Constantly Singing] (Box 72, Folder 50)
    - "The Song Goes On," in Fortnight, October/November 1980 [review of Constantly Singing] (Box 72, Folder 51)
    - "Sounds of Sense," by Peter Forbes, in The Listener, 5 March 1987 [review of Poems 1956-1986] (Box 72, Folder 52)
    - "Taking a Strong Line," in The Times Literary Supplement, 5 October 1967 [review of Late but in Earnest] [See Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - "Teller of Truths," by Basil Payne, in Books Ireland, December 1978 [review of The Selected James Simmons] (Box 72, Folder 53)
    - "This Champagne of Beers," by William Scammell, in The Spectator, 9 May 1987 [Review of Poems 1956-1986] (Box 72, Folder 54)
    - "Time to Move On," by Michael Foley [review of The Long Summer Still to Come] (Box 72, Folder 55)
    - "Tremblings of Promise," by Ian Hamilton [review of In the Wilderness] [See Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - "True to the Everyday," by Martin Booth in Tribune, 6 March 1987 [review of Poems 1956-1986] (Box 72, Folder 56)
    - "Two Irish Poets," by James Liddy in The Irish Times [review of Constantly Singing] (Box 72, Folder 57)
    - "Two Young Poets in a Different Vein," by Bruce Arnold in the Sunday Independent, 28 July 1967 [review of Late but in Earnest] [See Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - "Uncommonly Good," by Michael Foley, October 1978 [review of The Selected James Simmons] (Box 72, Folder 58)
    - "Visions of Life and Death," by Richard Kell, in The Guardian, 11 August 1967 [review of Late but in Earnest] [See Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - "Words Apart" by David Manicom in Graph [review of Poems 1956-1986 and Seamus Heaney's The Haw Lantern] (Box 72, Folder 59)
    - "A Worthy Quartet," by John Jordan in Poetry Ireland Review, Autumn 1987 [review of Poems 1956-1986] (Box 72, Folder 60)
    - "The Wounded Badger," by Michael Longley [review of In the Wilderness] [See Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - Review Checklist (Box 72, Folder 61)
    - Profiles and Promotional Items
    - "Ashes and Diamonds," by Claire Tomalin (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - "At the Court of King Simmons," by Paul Durcan in The Cork Examiner, 3 July 1978 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - "Blackstaff Flag Flying High," by Paul Durcan in The Cork Examiner, 15 January 1979 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - "Book Chat: The Best of '69," in Hibernia, 9 January 1970 [see Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - "Book Making," by Robert Taylor in Boston Sunday Globe, 20 May 1984 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - "British Poetry Since 1970," Selected by Michael McKenzie (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - "Cattle Rustling Irish-style" (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - "Election Runners Hold 'Hands Across the Divide' Ceremony in Ballymoney," in The Chronicle, 1 June 1996 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - "An English Mission," in Books Ireland, May 1985 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - "A Gifted Young Poet" [See Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - "A Halt at Culleybackey," by Benedict Kiely [see Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - "Irish Poet's Visit" [See Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - "An Irishman's Diary," 16 August 1968 [See Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - "An Irishman's Diary," 17 February 1977 (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - "An Irishman's Diary," by Niall Kiely, 1980 (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - "An Irishwoman's Diary," by Rosita Boland (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - "Ironing Out Simmons's Verse," by John McEntee in Irish Press, 14 May 1985 (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - "James Simmons," by James J. Murphy in Dictionary of Literary Biography (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - "James Simmons-A Man of Many Talents" (Box 73, Folder 14)
    - "James Simmons' Drumslade," by Billy Simpson in Belfast Telegraph, 19 October 1982 (Box 73, Folder 15)
    - "Join James for a Romantic Word on Valentine's Day," Times, 8 February 1996 (Box 73, Folder 16)
    - "A Leeds 'Juno and the Paycock'" (Box 73, Folder 17)
    - "Life Lines Win Praise," by Fiona McGarry (Box 73, Folder 18)
    - "A Little More of the Sense of Ireland" (Box 73, Folder 19)
    - "Local Poets Making a Great Impression" (Box 73, Folder 20)
    - "MacMillan Modern Dramatists Newsletter No. 4" (Box 73, Folder 21)
    - "Magazine Scene," by John Jordon, in The Irish Press, 28 March 1970 [see Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - "My Book of the Year," by Anthony Cronin, 29 December 1978 (Box 73, Folder 22)
    - "New Outlet for Our Literary 'Intellectuals,'" by Ralph Bossence, in News Letter (Box 73, Folder 23)
    - "New Ulster Poets," by Padraic Fiacc in Hibernia, November 1967 [See Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - "New Works Come After Tour," in Times News (Box 73, Folder 24)
    - Obituary for F. Stewart Simmons (Box 73, Folder 25)
    - "Of Youth and Young Love," by Ralph Bossenece, in News Letter, 19 August 1969 [See Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - "The Orpheus of Ulster," in The New York Review of Books, 11 July 1996 (Box OP11)
    - "Plain Truths & Home Cooking," by John Mole in Books & Writers (Box 73, Folder 26)
    - "Poems and Songs of Ulster" by Steven Winnett in the Queen's Journal, 19 March 1974 (Box 73, Folder 27)
    - "Poet Ignored," by Ralph Bossence in News Letter, 24 January 1968 [See also Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1] (Box 73, Folder 28)
    - "Poet in Print, in Person," by Joy Bannister in Spectator, 5 May 1978 (Box 73, Folder 29)
    - "Poetry, the Other Northern Ireland Ferment," by Peter Lennon in The Times, 11 April 1985 (Box 73, Folder 30)
    - "Popular T.V. Folk Singer," by Nomad (Box 73, Folder 31)
    - "Profundity Without the Po-Face," by Ciaran Carty in The Sunday Tribune, 22 March 1987 (Box 73, Folder 32)
    - "The Pushkin Prizes, School's Prize 1990" (Box 73, Folder 33)
    - "Sadly Wise Lyricism of James Simmons," by Tom Carson in The Belfast Telegraph, 24 August 1967
    - "Simmons Owes Much to the Folk Idiom," by Oliver Kennedy [See also Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1] (Box 73, Folder 34)
    - "Still Burning: James Simmons in Conversation with Martin Mooney" (Box 73, Folder 35)
    - "Telling Tales," by Alan Hollinghurst in Encounter, February/March 1981 (Box 73, Folder 36)
    - "Â£360-The Price James Simmons Paid for Being an Honest Ulsterman," by Brian Bell [See Subseries 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - "Tracey Tunes in to Ulster Poets," by Des McMullen (Box 73, Folder 37)
    - "A Triumph for Young Producer," by Desmond Pratt (Box 73, Folder 38)
    - "Ulster Poets and the Protestant Muse," by James Liddy in Books and Authors (Box 73, Folder 39)
    - "Ulsterman's Diary," by Chichester (Box 73, Folder 40)
    - "Ulster's Poets in Verse Get Together" in the Belfast Telegraph, 31 January 1991 (Box 73, Folder 41)
    - "Writing Round-About," by Adrian Barlow [See Suberies 3.5, Notebooks, Box 47, Folder 1]
    - "Yacht Safe" (Box 73, Folder 42)
    - Miscellaneous brief profiles (Box 73, Folder 43)
    - Miscellaneous publications about family (Box 73, Folder 44)
    - Untitled (Box 73, Folder 45)
    - Promotional items [folder 1 of 2] (Box 73, Folder 46)
    - Promotional items [folder 2 of 2] (Box 73, Folder 47)
    - Amnesty International Poetry Reading and Music (Box OP12)
    - Ramelton Georgian Society Swilly Poetry and Literary Group Reading (Box OP13)
    - Reading at the Duke's Head Theatre Club (Box OP14)
    - Reading at the Ulster Museum, 11 February 1996 (Box OP15)
    - Scrapbooks of clippings
    - Scrapbook (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Other printed material, Subseries 6.3; Box 75-77; OP 16-20
    - Individual Printed Works
    - Buchanan, George, "Song for Straphangers" (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Burns, Jim, Saloon Bar (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Clarke, John Cooper, "I Wrote the Songs" in Poetry Postcard Quarterly, 1994 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Crowley, Finbar, "On Visiting O'Neill's Tomb in Rome" (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - de Freyne, Leo, "You Were Offering Me a Jam-tart" (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Eberhart, Richard, "Spite Fence" (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Ewart, Gavin, "Loving Unsuitable People" (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Foley, Michael "An Irish Short Story," in Fortnight, 16 November 1972 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Greacen, Robert, "St Andrew's Day, 1985," in The Spectator, 6 December (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Harrison, Tony, "The Pocket Wars of Peanuts Joe" (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - Hartnett, Michael, "A Visit to Castletown House," in The Irish Press, 14 August 1971 (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - Heaney, Seamus, "Bann Clay" (Box 75, Folder 12)
    - Heaney, Seamus, "The Belfast Harp Festival 1792" (Box 75, Folder 13)
    - Heaney, Seamus, "Bog Oak" (Box 75, Folder 14)
    - Heaney, Seamus, "Cairn-Maker" [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Heaney, Seamus, "Bog Oak"]
    - Heaney, Seamus, "An Evening At Killard" (Box 75, Folder 15)
    - Heaney, Seamus, "First Calf" in The Listener, 4 September 1969 (Box 75, Folder 16)
    - Heaney, Seamus, "Good-Night" (Box 75, Folder 17)
    - Heaney, Seamus, "Icon" [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Heaney, Seamus, "First Calf"]
    - Heaney, Seamus, "Idyll" [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Heaney, Seamus, "First Calf"]
    - Heaney, Seamus, "John Field" [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Heaney, Seamus, "The Belfast Harp Festival 1792"]
    - Heaney, Seamus, "Maighdean Mara" [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Heaney, Seamus, "An Evening At Killard"]
    - Heaney, Seamus, "Medallion" [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Heaney, Seamus, "First Calf"]
    - Heaney, Seamus, "Midnight" [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Heaney, Seamus, "First Calf"]
    - Heaney, Seamus, "Navvy" [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Heaney, Seamus, "First Calf"]
    - Heaney, Seamus, "Nerthus" [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Heaney, Seamus, "Bog Oak"]
    - Heaney, Seamus, "Oracle" [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Heaney, Seamus, "Bog Oak"]
    - Heaney, Seamus, "Serenades" [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Heaney, Seamus, "First Calf"]
    - Heaney, Seamus, "Shore Woman" (Box 75, Folder 18)
    - Heaney, Seamus, "Strange Fruit," [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Buchanan, George, "Song for Straphangers"]
    - Heaney, Seamus, "Traditions" [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Heaney, Seamus, "Bog Oak"]
    - Heaney, Seamus, "Whatever You Say, Say Nothing" (Box 75, Folder 19)
    - Heaney, Seamus, "Whinlands" [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Heaney, Seamus, "Bann Clay"]
    - Heaney, Seamus, "A Winter's Tale" (Box 75, Folder 20)
    - Henderson, Hamish, "The Horseman's Word" (Box 75, Folder 21)
    - Hewett, Dorothy, "Legend of the Green Country" (Box 75, Folder 22)
    - Hewitt, John, "On Reading Terence de Vere White's Comment on Landor" (Box 75, Folder 23)
    - Hewitt, John, "The Search" (Box 75, Folder 24)
    - Kelly, Joe, "Lines on a Thuderstorm" [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Hartnett, Michael, "A Visit to Castletown House"]
    - Kelly, Joe, "The Strike," [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Hartnett, Michael, "A Visit to Castletown House"]
    - Kipling, Rudyard, "If" (Box OP16)
    - Large, Gillian, "On Ash Wednesday" [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Hartnett, Michael, "A Visit to Castletown House"]
    - Longley, Michael, "Mountain Swim" (Box 75, Folder 25)
    - Mahon, Derek, "An Image from Beckett" (Box 75, Folder 26)
    - Marno, David Cajeton, Poems (Box 75, Folder 27)
    - Martin, Augustine, "A Sketch" (Box 75, Folder 28)
    - Matthews, Tom, "The Dead Saviour" [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Crowley, Finbar, "On Visiting O'Neill's Tomb in Rome"]
    - Matthews, Tom, "Diffuse" [See Subeseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Crowley, Finbar, "On Visiting O'Neill's Tomb in Rome"]
    - Matthews, William, "On the Porch at the Frost Place, Franconia, N.H.," in The Atlantic Monthly (Box 75, Folder 29)
    - Matthews, William, "Snow Leopards at the Denver Zoo" (Box 75, Folder 30)
    - Miranda, Gary, "Horse Chestnut" (Box 75, Folder 31)
    - Montgomery, Derek, "A Letter From America" (Box 75, Folder 32)
    - Montgomery, Derek, "Nativity" (Box 75, Folder 33)
    - Moya, Carmela, Against All Odds (Box 75, Folder 34)
    - Muldoon, Paul, "Defence of Poesie" (Box 75, Folder 35)
    - Muldoon, Paul, "Duffy's Circus" [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Buchanan, George, "Song for Straphangers"]
    - Muldoon, Paul, "The Upriver Incident" (Box 75, Folder 36)
    - Muldoon, Paul, "The Waking Father" [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Muldoon, Paul, "The Upriver Incident"]
    - Mullen, Michael, "The Gaps Between the Stars" [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Hartnett, Michael, "A Visit to Castletown House"]
    - Murphy, Paul, "Cyclops [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, de Freyne, Leo, "You Were Offering Me a Jam-tart"]
    - Ní Chuilleanáin, Eiléan, "Refuge," in The Irish Press, 21 August 1971 (Box 75, Folder 37)
    - Ní Chuilleanáin, Eiléan, "Waterfall" [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Ní Chuilleanáin, Eiléan, "Refuge"]
    - Ní Dhomhniall, Nuala, "Parthenogenesis" (Box 75, Folder 38)
    - Ní Dhomhniall, Nuala, "We Are Damned My Sisters" ["Taimid Damanta, A Dheirfearacha"] (Box 75, Folder 39)
    - O'Connor, Frank, "The Call" [See Subseries 6.3, Other Printed Material, Ní Chuilleanáin, Eiléan, "Refuge"]
    - Ormsby, Frank, "Poem" (Box 75, Folder 40)
    - Reid, Forrest, Young Tom Book Jacket (Box 75, Folder 41)
    - Weir, Anthony, "Beached" (Box 75, Folder 42)
    - Wright, James "The Old WPA Swimming Pool in Martins Ferry, Ohio" (Box 75, Folder 43)
    - Unidentified Poetry (Box 75, Folder 44)
    - Magazines and Pamphlets
    - Advice to Authors (Box 75, Folder 45)
    - Bulletin, 26 February 1979 and 14 May, 1979 (Box 75, Folder 46)
    - Coleraine Musical Festival Programme, 1951 (Box 75, Folder 47)
    - Crann Newsletter, Spring 1987 and Autumn 1987 (Box 75, Folder 48)
    - The Dissenter, Summer 1986 (Box 75, Folder 49)
    - The Globe and Mail, 11 November 1972 (Box 75, Folder 50)
    - Gown Literary Supplement 1984 (Box 75, Folder 51)
    - Haiku Spirit, June 1995 (Box 75, Folder 52)
    - "John Hewitt, The Universal Poet: An Appreciation by Seamus Heaney" (Box 75, Folder 53)
    - New Ireland Group pamphlets (Box 75, Folder 54)
    - New Statesman, 6 December 1958 (Box 75, Folder 55)
    - NewsWrite, July 1994, December 1994-January 1995 (Box 75, Folder 56)
    - Ourselves and Others (Box 75, Folder 57)
    - Peterloo Poets: Stocklist 1984/85 (Box 75, Folder 58)
    - Poetry and Audience, 6 February 1959 (Box 75, Folder 59)
    - Poetry and Audience, 6 March 1970 (Box 75, Folder 60)
    - Poetry Ireland, November-December 1988, and April-June 1994 (Box 75, Folder 61)
    - Poetry News, Autumn 1992, and Spring 1993 (Box 75, Folder 62)
    - The Pushkin Prizes pamphlet (Box 75, Folder 63)
    - The Pushkin Prizes, Schools' Prize 1989 pamphlet (Box 75, Folder 64)
    - "Robert Emmet's 'Speech from the Dock'" (Box 75, Folder 65)
    - True Love (Box 75, Folder 66)
    - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings
    - Education (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Literary figures (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Northern Ireland conflict (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Religion (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Reviews (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Promotional Material
    - Promotional items (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Promotional items (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Poster for Christy Moore at the Ballyshannon Festival (Box OP17)
    - Poster for Circus Senso (Box OP18)
    - Poster for the Coleraine Festival of Culture, 1992 (Box OP19)
    - Poster for Low Profile (Box OP20)
- Photographs, Series 7; Box 78
  The series contains various photographs of Simmons, his family, and others.
  - James Simmons (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Simmons and family (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Other photographs (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Negatives (Box 78, Folder 4)